American Civil Liberties Union Records: Subgroup 2, Audiovisual Materials Series, 1947-1995: Finding Aid MC001.02.06
EADs for public policy collection from import batch
During the processing of this collection, many items were discarded, including newspaper clippings from the New York Times and other major newspapers, government publications, well- known serial publications, and publications and large distribution memoranda from well-known and well-documented organizations such as the American Jewish Committee or Americans United for the Separation of Church and State.
Existence and Location of Copies
Public records of the ACLU from 1917 to 1989, have been microfilmed by the Microfilming Corporation of America (MCA) and University Microfilms International (UMI). These records include minutes of the board of directors, mailings to the board of directors, biennial conference papers, policy guides, the national legal docket, organization manuals, constitution and bylaws, legal briefs, and publications. The American Civil Liberties Union Records and Publications 1917-1975: A Guide to the Microfilm Edition and succeeding guides to these materials are available in the reference room, and the microfilm itself is located in the microforms reading room.
The bound volumes of ACLU records covering 1917 through 1946 (volumes 1-2762) have been microfilmed and researchers must use the microfilm in order to prevent further deterioration of the these fragile volumes. Researchers should consult the finding aid to the earlier ACLU records (1917-1946) for their description and arrangement.
Related Materials
American Civil Liberties Union, Washington, D.C. Office Records
American United for the Separation of Church and State Records
Roger N. Baldwin Papers
Osmond K. Fraenkel Diaries
Fund for the Republic Records
Arthur Garfield Hays Papers
Peggy Lamson Collection on Roger N. Baldwin
Law Students Civil Rights Research Council Records
PEN American Center Records (at Firestone Library)
Bibliography
Historical sketch based on In Defense of American Liberties: A History of the ACLU by Samuel Walker. See also Samuel Walker's The American Civil Liberties Union: An Annotated Bibliography.
Abortion -- Law and legislation -- United States -- 20th century.; African Americans -- Civil rights -- History 20th century.; African Americans -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- 20th century.; Aliens -- United States -- Civil rights -- 20th century.; Amnesty -- United States -- 20th century.; Anti-Communist movements -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Apportionment (Election law) -- United States -- 20th century.; Assembly, Right of -- United States -- 20th century.; Censorship -- United States -- 20th century.; Church and state --United States -- 20th century.; Citizen suits (Civil procedure) -- United States -- 20th century.; Civil rights -- United States -- 20th century.; Civil rights movements -- United States -- 20th century.; Civil rights workers -- United States -- 20th Century -- Correspondence.; Communism -- United States -- 20th century.; Conscientious objectors -- United States -- 20th century.; Constitutional law -- United States -- 20th century.; Discrimination -- United States -- 20th century.; Discrimination in employment - Law and legislation - United States - 20th century.; Draft resisters -- United States -- 20th century.; Due process of law -- United States -- 20th century.; Equality before the law -- United States -- 20th century.; Freedom of association -- United States -- 20th century.; Freedom of information -- United States -- 20th century.; Freedom of movement -- United States --20th century.; Freedom of religion -- United States -- 20th century.; Gay rights -- United States -- 20th century.; Homosexuality -- Government policy -- History -- United States -- 20th century.; Indians of North America -- Civil rights -- 20th century.; Insanity -- Jurisprudence -- United States -- 20th century.; Internal security -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Jews -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States -- 20th century.; Labor laws and legislation -- United States -- 20th century.; Law -- United States -- Cases -- 20th century.; Legal aid -- United States -- 20th century.; Legal services -- United States -- 20th century.; Loyalty oaths -- United States -- 20th century.; Mental health laws -- United States -- 20th century.; Minorities -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States -- 20th century.; Police power -- United States -- 20th century.; Political questions and judicial power -- United States -- 20th century.; Political refugees -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States -- 20th century.; Political rights -- United States -- 20th century.; Political rights, Loss of -- United States -- 20th century.; Privacy, Right of - United States - 20th century.; Race discrimination -- Law and legislation -- United States -- 20th century.; Records -- Access control -- United States -- 20th century.; Sacco-Vanzetti Trial, Dedham, Mass., 1921.; Sex discrimination -- United States -- 20th century.; Strikes and lockouts -- United States -- Cases - 20th century.; Subversive activities -- United States -- 20th century.; Teaching, Freedom of -- United States -- 20th century.; Television in politics -- United States -- 20th century.; Trials -- United States -- 20th century.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- United States.; Women's rights -- United States -- 20th century.; United States -- Armed forces -- Gays.; Audiovisual materials.; Briefs.; Correspondence.; Legal files.; Memorandums.; Minutes.; Reports.; American history/20th century; American politics and government; Legal history; Public policy/20th century; World War II; World War I
- Series 6, Audio-Visual materials, 1930-1995; 70 boxes; 1 folder; 2 items
  Scope and Contents
  The Audio Visual Series contains VHS video cassette tapes, Beta video cassette tapes, 1" and 2" video tape, 16 mm film, 2-inch videotape, microfilm, audio cassettes, 33 1/3 rpm and 45 rpm records, photographs, and reel-to-reel audio tapes. All of the audio-visual material is arranged by format, then chronologically, except for the photographs which are arranged alphabetically by subject or individual.
  The VHS video tapes contain a few sessions from the 1989 Biennial Conference, but primarily consist of TV talk shows, press conferences, network news, and documentaries covering a wide range of civil liberties issues. Most shows feature one or more ACLU-affiliated guests. The VHS tapes span 1979 through 1992, and 1995.
  The audio cassettes consist almost entirely of recordings of the sessions from the 1985, 1987, and 1989 Biennial Conferences. Also included are three tapes from Series 3, Subject Files: Deprogramming. For the 1985 Conference, a list of the presenter(s) of the various sessions is provided, however, this information was not available for the 1987 and 1989 Conferences.
  The reel-to-reel audio tapes are divided into two sections: seven-inch reels and five-inch reels. The seven-inch reels contain debates involving Fulton Lewis III from the early 1960s, recordings from the 1970 Biennial Conference, and various ACLU board meetings from 1973-1976. The five-inch reels contain ACLU public service announcements. There are a few reels, both seven- inch and five-inch, that are presently unidentified.
  The 16mm films include TV shows and films that the ACLU had significant interest in, including "Operation Abolition," a 1960 propaganda film prepared by the House Committee on Un-American Activities distorting the events of a student protest against the HUAC hearings in San Francisco. Also included is the response film "Operation Correction."
  The photographs are primarily portraits and group photos of ACLU officials. Negatives for some of the photographs are also enclosed. There are also a few slides. The 2" video tapes consist of eight reels from the "Rights of Americans" series and "commercial spots" for the Amnesty Project.
  Arrangement
  Series 6 is arranged by form and alphabetically or chronologically therein.
  - VHS Cassette Tapes, 1979 March-1995; 16 boxes; 2 items
    - 60 Minutes, Roger Baldwin interview, 1979 March 11; 1979-1; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer Report; Roger Baldwin, 1979 April 25; 1979-2; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - Copy of Tapes 1979-1 and 1979-2: MacNeil-Lehrer Report; Roger Baldwin, 1979 March-1979 April; 1 box (Box 5676)
      U-matic, KSP-S20
    - Phil Donahue, The Moral Majority; Ira Glasser, 1981; 1981-1; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - C-SPAN, Libel Law Call-In Program; Ira Glasser, 1984 December 13; 1984-1; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - World News Tonite, The Sanctuary: Nuns Hiding Illegal Aliens, 1985 May 27; 1985-1; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - Constitution at 200, The Constitution; Burt Neuborne, 1986 April 2; 1986-1; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - Rights in Jeopardy, Gay Rights and AIDS: The role of the ACLU; Dave Waxy, John Barboni (KC), Tom Stoddard, 1986; 1986-2; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - Main Street (NBC), Euthanasia; Nancy Cruzan, 1986; 1986-3; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - Phil Donahue, AIDS Testing; Nan Hunter, 1986; 1986-4; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - Phil Donahue, various shows, Drug Testing; Ira Glasser, 1986; 1986-5; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - ICWU Convention, Drug Testing in the Workplace; Ira Glasser, others, 1986; 1986-6; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - ICWU Convention, Drug Testing in the Workplace; Ira Glasser, others, 1986; 1986-7; 1 box (Box 2036)
    - MacNeil Lehrer, Preventative Detention: Jail Without Bail; Al Bronstein, 1987 January 21; 1987-1; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Bill Moyers Documentary, In Search of the Constitution: National Defense, Drugs, Abortion, etc, 1987 June 7; 1987-2; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Bill Moyers Documentary, In Search of the Constitution: 1987 v. the Constitution, 1987 June 7; 1987-2a; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Indiana CLU TV ad, Know Your Rights about the Bill of Rights, 1987 August 20; 1987-3; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - C-SPAN, Nomination of Robert Bork: ACLU opposes; Norman Dorsen, Ira Glasser, Halperin, Powell, 1987 August 31; 1987-4; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - We The People 200, The Constitutional Gala, 1987 October 16; 1987-5; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - We The People 200, The Constitutional Gala, 1987 October 16; 1987-6; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Bill Moyers Special Report, The Secret Government... The Constitution in Crisis, Iran Contra Affair (Pt. 1), 1987 November 4; 1987-7; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Bill Moyers Special Report, The Secret Government... The Constitution in Crisis, Iran Contra Affair (Pt. 2), 1987 November 4; 1987-8; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Town Meeting, Race and the Constitution: A Panel; Wade Henderson, 1987 November 12; 1987-9; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - CBS News Nightwatch, Abortion and Forced C- sections; Lynn Paltrow, 1987 December; 1987-10; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - Good Morning America, Reproductive Freedom: Forced C-sections; Lynn Paltrow, 1987 December 2; 1987-11; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - CNN - Sonya Live, Abortions and father's rights; Lynn Paltrow, 1987; 1987-12; 1 box (Box 2037)
    - CCLU Documentary, The Death Penalty; Bill Olds, Diane Rust-Tierney, others, 1987; 1987-13; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Firing Line, The Legalization of Drugs; Ira Glasser, 1987; 1987-14; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Copy of Firing Line, The Legalization of Drugs; Ira Glasser, 1987; 1 box (Box 5676)
      Betacam SP
    - Phil Donahue, The Ku Klux Klan's right to be on television; Ira Glasser, Hosea Williams, 1987; 1987-15; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Documentary Program, Justice Is A Constant Struggle; Ira Glasser, 1987; 1987-16; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - This Week with David Brinkley, Bork Nomination, 1987; 1987-17; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - This Week with David Brinkley, Bork Nomination; Norman Dorsen, 1987; 1987-17a; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Geraldo, Forced C-sections; Lynn Paltrow, 1988 January; 1988-1; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - WCBS News (Channel 2), DYFS: Division of Youth and Family Services; New Jersey government, 1988 February 24-26; 1988-2; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Phil Donahue, Homeless or Mentally Ill: Joyce Brown; Norman Siegel, Rob Levy, 1988 Spring; 1988-3; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Phil Donahue, Faith Healing or Child Abuse; Marcia Robinson Lowry, 1988 May 17; 1988-4; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Morton Downey Jr., Gun Control; Steve Hyman, 1988 June 9; 1988-5; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - Phil Donahue, Censorship: Harold Washington painting, etc.; Harvey Grossman, 1988 June 14; 1988-6; 1 box (Box 2038)
    - CNN coverage, Republican National Convention; Pat Robertson, 1988 August; 1988-7; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - ABC Town Meeting, Legalization of Drugs: with Ted Koppel; Dershowitz, Buckley, others, 1988 September 13; 1988-8; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - Town Meeting II, The Legalization of Drugs, 1988 September 13; 1988-9; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - Crossfire, Bush's attacks on the ACLU; Danny Goldberg, 1988 Fall; 1988-10; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - C-SPAN coverage, Speech to the National Press Club; Ira Glasser, 1988 October 6; 1988-11; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - (Items 12-14 removed: duplicates), dates not examined; 1 item
    - Headlines on Trial, Mothers' Rights v. Fetuses Rights; Lynn Paltrow, 1988 October 26; 1988-15; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - Travelling Hopefully, Roger Baldwin and the ACLU, a film by John Avildsen; Roger Baldwin, 1988; 1988-16; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - Copy of Travelling Hopefully, Roger Baldwin and the ACLU, a film by John Avildsen; Roger Baldwin, 1988; 1 box (Box 5676)
      U-matic, KSP-60
    - ACLU PSAS, Card-Carrying Members; Burt Lancaster, Jill Eikenberry, Michael Tucker, 1988 September; 1988-17; 1 box (Box 2039)
    - 1989 Biennial Convention, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Opening Plenary, dates not examined; 1; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Civil Liberties and The Drug Crisis (NY Office Copy), dates not examined; 2; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Civil Liberties and The Drug Crisis, dates not examined; 3; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Public Education on the Bill of Rights, dates not examined; 4; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Racism on the Rise, dates not examined; 5; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Today's Challenge to the Bill of Rights, dates not examined; 6; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Closing Banquet, dates not examined; 7; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - National and Affiliate Reports, dates not examined; 8; 1 box (Box 2040)
      - Freedom Follies; Melissa Goes to Madison, WI, dates not examined; 9; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - ABC News Nightline, Capital Punishment; Henry Schwarzschild, 1989 January 23; 1989-1; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - Oprah Winfrey, Pornography; Barry Lynn, 1989 February 7; 1989-2; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - People are Talking, Capital Punishment in NY; Henry Schwarzschild, 1989 March 9; 1989-3; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - People are Talking, Drug Testing in Public High Schools; Loren Siegel, 1989 March 14; 1989-3; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - It's Your Business, Crime and Punishment and Prisons; Alvin Bronstein and Ed Meese, 1989 April 2; 1989-4; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - ABC News Nightline, Evictions from Public Housing for Drug Use; John Powell, 1989 April 1; 1989-5; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - ABC News Nightline, Corporate Spying; Ira Glasser, 1989 April 1; 1989-5; 1 box (Box 2040)
    - People are Talking, Pornography; Lorraine Stanley, 1989 May 18; 1989-6; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Crossfire, Arresting the Parents of Criminals; Ramona Ripson, 1989 Spring; 1989-7; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Geraldo, Pregnancy Police; Lynn Paltrow, 1989 May 2; 1989-8; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Taking Liberties, Glimpses of the ACLU; Everybody, 1989 June 1; 1989-9; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Donahue, Flag Burning; Ira Glasser, Bill Kunstler, Greg Johnson and Bob Dornan, 1989 June; 1989-10; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Sonya! Live from L.A., Capital Punishment for the Young and Retarded; Henry Schwarzschild, 1989 June; 1989-11; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - CNN Live, Arresting Pregnant Women for Drug Use/Child Abuse; Lynn Paltrow, 1989 July 13; 1989-12; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - CNN Live, Flag Burning and Life Amendments; John Sununu Press Conference, 1989 July; 1989-13; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - People are Talking, Punishing the Parents of Juvenile Criminals; Norman Siegel, 1989 July; 1989-14; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Entertainment Tonight, Racial Hatred Movies, Klan TV; Ira Glasser; ABC Documentary "Black in White America", Race Relations, 1989 August; 1989-15; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - ACLU Crime Conference, Keynote Adress; Sam Dash, 1989 September 14; 1989-16; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Firing Line, "Was the Supreme Court Wrong About Flag Burning?" Ira Glasser, 1989 September 1; 1989-17A; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Firing Line, "Was the Supreme Court Wrong About Flag Burning?" Ira Glasser, 1989 September 1; 1989-17B; 1 box (Box 2041)
    - Firing Line, "Was the Supreme Court Wrong About Flag Burning?" Ira Glasser, 1989 September 1; 1989-17C; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - ACLU Censorship Video, Censorship; None, 1989 October 1; 1989-18; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - Jane Wallace Show, Punishing Parents of Criminals; Jay Jacobson, 1989 November 2; 1989-19; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - FNN Focus, Legalization of Drugs; Loren Siegel, 1989 November 4; 1989-20; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - Wisconsin Seminar, Free Expression; Eunice Edgar, 1989 November 4; 1989-21; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - Saturday Night with Connie Chung, Minors' Abortion Rights; Janet Benshoof, 1989 November 1; 1989-22; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - CBS Morning News, FBI Spying on Innocent People; Frank Askin, 1989 November 2; 1989-23; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - People are Talking, Women in the Army; Isabelle Katz Pinzler, 1989 November 2; 1989-24; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - C-SPAN Coverage, Minors' Abortion Rights; Jane Hodgson and Simon Heller, 1989 November 2; 1989-25; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer, Minors' Abortion Rights; Janet Benshoof, 1989 November 2; 1989-26; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - South Africa Now, Immigration of South African Dissidents; Lucas Guttentag, 1989 November 2; 1989-27; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - Network Coverage, Nancy Cruzan's Right to Die; William Colby, 1989 December 6; 1989-28; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - C-SPAN SCOTUS Review, Nancy Cruzan's Right to Die; William Colby, 1989 December 9; 1989-29; 1 box (Box 2042)
    - PBS Frontline, Nancy Cruzan's Right to Die; William Colby, Everett Koop, Nat Hentoff and Fred Friendly, 1989 December 13; 1989-30; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - ABC World News Tonight, Sex Discrimination in the Work Place; Joan Bertin, 1989 December 1; 1989-31; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Northern California Clips, Various; Various, 1989 April-November; 1989-32; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - VH-1 Reefer Madness Redux, The Current Drug Crackdown; Loren Siegel, 1990 January; 1990-1; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - CNN Coverage, The War on Drugs; George Bush, Joseph Biden, 1990 January 27; 1990-2; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Taking Liberties II, Glimpses of the ACLU, 1990 February 1; 1990-3A; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Taking Liberties II, Glimpses of the ACLU, 1990 February 1; 1990-3B; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Taking Liberties II, Glimpses of the ACLU, 1990 February 1; 1990-3C; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Collected Footage, The War on Drugs; for Loren Siegel, 1990 February 1; 1990-4; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Cityscope, Drug Testing; Loren Siegel, 1990 February 23; 1990-5; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Jane Wallace Show, Drug Testing; Loren Siegel, 1990 February 12; 1990-6; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - The Constitution: That Delicate Balance, Drugs, Crime, etc., Nadine Strossen (first 2 of 4), 1990 February 5; 1990-7A; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - The Constitution: That Delicate Balance, Drugs, Crime, etc.; Nadine Strossen (last 2 of 4), 1990 February 19; 1990-7B; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - ABC News/McNeil-Lehrer, Sobriety Checkpoints; Mark Granzotto, 1990 February 27; 1990-8; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Press Conference, Children's Rights in Kansas; Marcia Robinson Lowry, 1990 February; 1990-9; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - Federalist Society Debate, The ACLU's Mission and Integrity; Norman Dorsen and William Donohue, 1990 March 8; 1990-10; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - NBC NewsCenter 4, Spying at Home: Secret Surveillance Devices; Loren Siegel, 1990 March 12; 1990-11; 1 box (Box 2043)
    - CBS News Nightwatch, Death Penalty; Henry Schwarzschild, 1990 March 28; 1990-12; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - Press Conference, Children's Rights in Pennsylvania; Marcia Robinson Lowry, 1990 April 3; 1990-13; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - The Eleventh Hour, Child Abuse; Marcia Robinson Lowry, 1990 April 9; 1990-14; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - Geraldo, Parental Consent; Janet Benshoof, 1990 April 12; 1990-15; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - Oprah Winfrey, Corporal Punishment; Paul Denenfield, 1990 April 26; 1990-15; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - Joan Rivers, Publishing Names of Prostitutes; Deborah Ellis, 1990 April 26; 1990-16; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - ABC News Nightline, Drunk Driving Roadblocks; Mark Granzotto, 1990 May 25; 1990-17; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - Sonya Live on CNN, Punishing People Who Commit Crimes Because They Have a Disease; Nadine Strossen, 1990 June 12; 1990-18; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - ABC World News Tonight, NBC Nightly News, Good Morning America, Drunk Driving Roadblocks; Nadine Strossen, 1990 June 15; 1990-19; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - The Koppel Report, "Drugs, Crime, and Doing Time"; None, 1990 September 5; 1990-20; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - America's Drug Forum, A War on Drugs or a War on Constitutional Rights?; Ira Glasser, 1990 September; 1990-21; 1 box (Box 2044)
    - Firing Line, Death Penalty; Henry Schwarzschild, 1990 October 6; 1990-22; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - Copy of Firing Line, Death Penalty; Henry Schwarzschild, 1990 October 6; 1 box (Box 5676)
    - ABC World News Tonight, Tacit Speech Codes; Brady Williamson, 1990 November 1; 1990-22; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - CNBC-McLaughlin, The ACLU's Integrity; Ira Glasser, 1990 October 1; 1990-23; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - ACLU Press Conference after Rust v. Sullivan, Abortion Counseling; Rachael Pine and Laurence Tribe, 1990 October 3; 1990-24; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - C-SPAN Coverage, Rust v. Sullivan; Rachael Pine, 1990 October 3; 1990-25; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour, Rust v. Sullivan; Laurence Tribe, 1990 October 3; 1990-26; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - Sonya Live on CNN, Black Male Only Schools; Norman Siegel, 1990 November; 1990-27; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - ACLU Press Conference, A State of Emergency in the American Workplace; Lew Maltby, 1990 December 1; 1990-28; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - First Amendment Congress, 45 Words of Freedom: The Meaning of the First Amendment; Allan Adler, 1990; 1990-29; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - Idaho CLU Appearance, Anti-abortion Laws; Jack Van Valkenbergh, 1990; 1990-30; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - ABC World News Tonight, Civil Liberties in the Persian Gulf; Ira Glasser, 1991 January 28; 1991-1; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer Report, Police Brutality in L.A.; Ramona Ripston, 1991 March 15; 1991-1; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - ABC News 20/20, Gays in the Military, 1991 March 8; 1991-2; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - Crossfire, Justify the Video: Obscenity in Madonna's Video; Danny Goldberg, 1991 March 18; 1991-3; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - CBS Evening News, Police Brutality in L.A.; Ramona Ripston, 1991 March 20; 1991-4; 1 box (Box 2045)
    - Sonya Live on CNN, Coerced Confessions; Steve Shapiro, 1991 March 26; 1991-5; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - Donahue Show, Forced Contraception; Julie Mertus, 1991 March 28; 1991-5; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - CNN Crier and Co., Victim's Rights; Vivian Berger, 1991 April 16; 1991-6; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - Thirteen Live, Children's Rights; Marcia Robinson Lowry, 1991 May 15; 1991-7; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - C-SPAN Coverage, Rust v. Sullivan Press Conference; Rachael Pine, 1991 May 23; 1991-8; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - PBS Special: Safe Speech, Free Speech and the University, Hate Speech on Campus; Nadine Strossen, 1991 June 6; 1991-9; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - ABC World News Tonight, Black Male Only Academies; Howard Simon, 1991 August 14; 1991-9; 1 box (Box 2046)
    - CBS News Nightwatch, Racist Speech on Campus; Nadine Strossen, 1991 August; 1991-10; 1 box (Box 2046)